dylanrandle.github.io | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

I am a highly skilled data scientist with a half decade of experience building artificial intelligence applications in **robotics**, **computer vision**, and **natural language processing**. My work has been published and patented, and I have presented it at top institutions like MIT and Harvard.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Scientist

North Reading, MA, USA

Amazon Robotics

Jul 2020 – Present

• Developed machine learning and optimization systems for robotic manipulation and path planning

- Responsible for performance improvements of up to +25% and estimated savings of +\$100MM
- Recipient of Inventor Award (x2)

Data ScientistToronto, ON, CanadaHubdocFeb 2017 – Jul 2018

- Developed machine learning system for natural language processing of financial documents
- Deployed to production with 99% precision at 95% recall, while reducing extraction time by 99.99%

EDUCATION

Harvard University Cambridge, MA, USA

Master of Science in Data Science (GPA: 4.0)

Aug 2018 – May 2020

• Scholarship in Applied Computation, Distinction in Teaching

University of California, BerkeleyBachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering & Operations Research (GPA: 3.9)

Berkeley, CA, USA Aug 2012 – May 2016

• High Honors (magna cum laude), Frank Kraft Award, Phi Beta Kappa, Tau Beta Pi, Alpha Pi Mu

PROJECTS

Grasp Learning for Robotic Item Manipulation

Amazon Robotics

- Developed Vision Transformer and PointNet++ models for learned grasp generation and ranking
- Achieved **+22% improvement** in grasp evaluation performance

Computer Vision for Robotic Damage Detection

Amazon Robotics

- Developed ResNet-based visual anomaly detection model for damage detection
- Achieved +25% improvement in damage detection performance

Simulation-Based Optimization for Robotic Path Planning

Amazon Robotics

- Developed simulation-based optimizer for **path planning** on fleets of thousands of mobile robots
- Achieved +10% improvement in robotic system throughput

Physics-Informed Neural Networks

Harvard University

- Developed generative adversarial networks for solving differential equations
- Workshop paper published at ICML 2022

SKILLS

- Languages: Python, C++, Javascript/Typescript, SQL
- Libraries: PyTorch, Keras/Tensorflow, OpenCV, Open3D, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Scikit-Learn, React
- Platforms: AWS, Docker, Firebase, Linux, MacOS